A Guide to the Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, Abby Aldrich Rockefeller, Series AA FA336
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Abby Aldrich Rockefeller Papers - Aldrich/Greene Family Papers, 1858-1949, n.d.; AA.5; 1 Document Box(es)
  - Correspondence of Abby Pearce Chapman Aldrich - Aldrich, William T., 1885, 1887, 1900 (Box 27, Folder 245)
  - Correspondence of Abby Pearce Chapman Aldrich - Pierce, Frank, 1916 (Box 27, Folder 246)
  - Correspondence of Abby Pearce Chapman Aldrich - Rockefeller, Abby Aldrich, 1885-1913, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 247)
  - Correspondence of Abby Pearce Chapman Aldrich - Rockefeller, John D., Jr., 1901-1905, 1907-1911, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 248)
  - Correspondence of Abby Pearce Chapman Aldrich - Rockefeller, Laura Spelman, 1901, 1903 (Box 27, Folder 249)
  - Diary of Abby Pearce Chapman Aldrich, 1858, 1879 (Box 27, Folder 250)
    With typescript excerpts, n.d.
  - Genealogical Material, 1926-1949, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 251)
  - Genealogy - "Ancestry of Nelson Wilmarth Aldrich and His Wife, Abby Pearce Truman Chapman", 1938 (Box 27, Folder 252)
  - Ira Pearce Family Correspondence, 1866, 1869 (Box 27, Folder 253)
  - Settlement - Estate of Duty Greene, 1864-1865 (Box 27, Folder 254)
- Abby Aldrich Rockefeller Papers - Death of Abby Aldrich Rockefeller, 1948, 1950, 1953, 1956; AA.6; 7 Document Box(es)
  Files are alphabetically arranged by subject or type of material.
  Subseries 6, Death of Abby Aldrich Rockefeller, contains clippings, condolences, and publicity occasioned by Abby's death in 1948.
  - Arrangements - Press, Flowers, 1948 (Box 28, Folder 255)
  - Clipping Book, 1948 (Box 28, Folder 256)
  - Clippings, 1948 (Box 28, Folder 257)
  - Clippings, Reproductions of, 1948 (Box 28, Folder 258)
  - Clippings, 1953 (Box 28, Folder 259)
  - Condolences - Index of Condolences Received, 1948 (Box 28, Folder 260)
  - Condolences (A) (Box 28, Folder 261)
  - Condolences (Ba) (Box 28, Folder 262)
  - Condolences (Be-Bl) (Box 28, Folder 263)
  - Condolences (Bo) (Box 28, Folder 264)
  - Condolences (Br-By) (Box 29, Folder 265)
  - Condolences (Ca) (Box 29, Folder 266)
  - Condolences (Ch-Cl) (Box 29, Folder 267)
  - Condolences (Coe-Con) (Box 29, Folder 268)
  - Condolences (Cot-Cuy) (Box 29, Folder 269)
  - Condolences (Dab-Deb) (Box 29, Folder 270)
  - Condolences (DeC-Dwi) (Box 29, Folder 271)
  - Condolences (E) (Box 29, Folder 272)
  - Condolences (Fa-Fl) (Box 30, Folder 273)
  - Condolences (Fo-Fu) (Box 30, Folder 274)
  - Condolences (Ga-Gi) (Box 30, Folder 275)
  - Condolences (Gl-Go) (Box 30, Folder 276)
  - Condolences (Haa-Heb) (Box 30, Folder 277)
  - Condolences (Hei-Hit) (Box 30, Folder 278)
  - Condolences (Ho-Hy) (Box 31, Folder 279)
  - Condolences (Ind-Joh) (Box 31, Folder 280)
  - Condolences (Jol-Jos) (Box 31, Folder 281)
  - Condolences (K) (Box 31, Folder 282)
  - Condolences (La) (Box 31, Folder 283)
  - Condolences (Le-Lu) (Box 31, Folder 284)
  - Condolences (McA-McG) (Box 31, Folder 285)
  - Condolences (McI-Man) (Box 31, Folder 286)
  - Condolences (Marasco-Merriman) (Box 32, Folder 287)
  - Condolences (Merritt-Mirabel) (Box 32, Folder 288)
  - Condolences (Mod-Mot) (Box 32, Folder 289)
  - Condolences (Mou-Mye) (Box 32, Folder 290)
  - Condolences (N-O) (Box 32, Folder 291)
  - Condolences (Pac-Pli) (Box 32, Folder 292)
  - Condolences (Plo-Qui) (Box 32, Folder 293)
  - Condolences (Ral-Rob) (Box 32, Folder 294)
  - Condolences (Roc-Ryl) (Box 33, Folder 295)
  - Condolences (Sa-Sc) (Box 33, Folder 296)
  - Condolences (Sea-Sim) (Box 33, Folder 297)
  - Condolences (Sin-Spu) (Box 33, Folder 298)
  - Condolences (St-Sy) (Box 33, Folder 299)
  - Condolences (T) (Box 33, Folder 300)
  - Condolences (U-V) (Box 33, Folder 301)
  - Condolences (Wad-War) (Box 33, Folder 302)
  - Condolences (Was-Whi) (Box 34, Folder 303)
  - Condolences (Wie-Wil) (Box 34, Folder 304)
  - Condolences (Win-Zor) (Box 34, Folder 305)
  - Condolences from Rockefeller Daughters-In-Law, 1948 (Box 34, Folder 306)
  - Memorial Service - Riverside Church, 1948 (Box 34, Folder 307)
  - Memorial Service - Williamsburg Baptist Church, 1948 (Box 34, Folder 308)
  - Memorial Service Booklet - Manuscript Drafts, 1948, 1950 (Box 34, Folder 309)
  - Memorial Window - Union Church, 1956 (Box 34, Folder 310)
  - Publicity, 1948 (Box 34, Folder 311)
- Abby Aldrich Rockefeller Papers - Chase Biography Files, 1948-1956, 1959, n.d.; AA.7; 4 Document Box(es)
  Subseries 7 is alphabetically arranged by type of material.
  Subseries 7, Chase Biography Files, includes John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s correspondence with Mary Ellen Chase, Abby's biographer, and with his office staff concerning arrangements for the publication and distribution of "Abby Aldrich Rockefeller" (1950). Also present are Chase's research materials, consisting of typed excerpts of Abby's correspondence, together with the original annotated typescript.
  - Correspondence of John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - General, 1948 (Box 35, Folder 312)
  - Correspondence of John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - General, January-March 1949 (Box 35, Folder 313)
  - Correspondence of John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - General, April-May 1949 (Box 35, Folder 314)
  - Correspondence of John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - General, June-July 1949 (Box 35, Folder 315)
  - Correspondence of John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - General, August-December 1949 (Box 35, Folder 316)
  - Correspondence of John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - General, January-February 1950 (Box 35, Folder 317)
  - Correspondence of John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - General, June-November 1950 (Box 35, Folder 318)
  - Correspondence of John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - General, 1951-1956, 1959 (Box 35, Folder 319)
  - Correspondence of John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Chase, Mary Ellen, January-June 1949 (Box 35, Folder 320)
  - Correspondence of John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Chase, Mary Ellen, July-December 1949 (Box 36, Folder 321)
  - Correspondence of John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Chase, Mary Ellen, January-February 1950 (Box 36, Folder 322)
  - Correspondence of John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Chase, Mary Ellen, March 1950 (Box 36, Folder 323)
  - Correspondence of John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Chase, Mary Ellen, April-October 1950 (Box 36, Folder 324)
  - Correspondence of John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Distribution of Book, 1950-1956 (Box 36, Folder 325)
  - Correspondence of John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Financial Arrangements, 1949-1951 (Box 36, Folder 326)
  - Correspondence of John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Letters of Acknowledgement (A-C), 1950-1951 (Box 36, Folder 327)
  - Correspondence of John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Letters of Acknowledgement (D-H), 1950-1951 (Box 36, Folder 328)
  - Correspondence of John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Letters of Acknowledgement (K-N), 1950-1951 (Box 36, Folder 329)
  - Correspondence of John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Letters of Acknowledgement (O-W), 1950-1951 (Box 36, Folder 330)
  - Correspondence of John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Publication in "Good Houskeeping", 1950, 1957 (Box 36, Folder 331)
  - Correspondence of John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Publication - Macmillan Company, 1949-1950, 1956 (Box 37, Folder 332)
  - Printed Material - "Good Houskeeping", June 1950 (Box 37, Folder 333)
  - Printed Material - "Good Houskeeping", July 1950 (Box 37, Folder 334)
  - Research Material - Condolences Received on Abby Aldrich Rockefeller's Death (Transcripts), 1948 (Box 37, Folder 335)
  - Research Material - Condolences Received on Abby Aldrich Rockefeller's Death (Transcripts), 1948 (Box 37, Folder 336)
  - Research Material - Condolences Received on Abby Aldrich Rockefeller's Death (Transcripts), 1948 (Box 37, Folder 337)
  - Research Material - Condolences Received on Abby Aldrich Rockefeller's Death (Transcripts), 1948 (Box 37, Folder 338)
  - Research Material - Condolences Received on Abby Aldrich Rockefeller's Death (Transcripts), 1948 (Box 37, Folder 339)
  - Research Material - Condolences Received on Abby Aldrich Rockefeller's Death by Lucy Truman Aldrich (Transcripts), 1948 (Box 37, Folder 340)
  - Research Material - Condolences Received on Abby Aldrich Rockefeller's Death by David Rockefeller (Transcripts), 1948 (Box 37, Folder 341)
  - Research Material - Condolences Received on Abby Aldrich Rockefeller's Death by Laurance Rockefeller (Transcripts), 1948 (Box 37, Folder 342)
  - Research Material - Condolences Received on Abby Aldrich Rockefeller's Death by Nelson A. Rockefeller (Transcripts), 1948 (Box 37, Folder 343)
  - Research Material - Correspondence (1917-1948) of Abby Aldrich Rockefeller - Copies and Excerpts, 1917-1922 (Box 38, Folder 344)
  - Research Material - Correspondence (1917-1948) of Abby Aldrich Rockefeller - Copies and Excerpts, 1923-1926 (Box 38, Folder 345)
  - Research Material - Correspondence (1917-1948) of Abby Aldrich Rockefeller - Copies and Excerpts, 1927-1929 (Box 38, Folder 346)
  - Research Material - Correspondence (1917-1948) of Abby Aldrich Rockefeller - Copies and Excerpts, 1930-1933 (Box 38, Folder 347)
  - Research Material - Correspondence (1917-1948) of Abby Aldrich Rockefeller - Copies and Excerpts, 1934-1938 (Box 38, Folder 348)
  - Research Material - Correspondence (1917-1948) of Abby Aldrich Rockefeller - Copies and Excerpts, 1941-1946 (Box 38, Folder 349)
  - Research Material - Correspondence (1917-1948) of Abby Aldrich Rockefeller - Copies and Excerpts, 1947-1948 (Box 38, Folder 350)
  - Research Material - Miscellaneous Notes and Reminiscences, 1949, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 351)
  - Research Material - Revised Manuscript Draft (Original Annotated Typescript) - "Abby Aldrich Rockefeller" - Chapters 1-3 (Box 38, Folder 352)
  - Research Material - Revised Manuscript Draft (Original Annotated Typescript) - "Abby Aldrich Rockefeller" - Chapters 4-8 (Box 38, Folder 353)
- Abby Aldrich Rockefeller Papers - Family Correspondence, 1915-1948; AA.8; 4 Document Box(es)
  This subseries is arranged in three sections: Outgoing Correspondence, Incoming Correspondence, and Children's Nurses Correspondence.
  - Outgoing Correspondence - Abby Rockefeller Mauzé, 1938 (Box 39, Folder 354)
  - Outgoing Correspondence - David Rockefeller, 1920-1925 (Box 39, Folder 355)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Open to scholarly access with prior archival review.
  - Outgoing Correspondence - David Rockefeller, 1927-1931, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 356)
  - Outgoing Correspondence - David Rockefeller, 1932-1937, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 357)
  - Outgoing Correspondence - David Rockefeller, August 10 and 17, 1934 (Box 39, Folder 0357A)
  - Outgoing Correspondence - David Rockefeller, 1938, 1943, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 358)
  - Outgoing Correspondence - David Rockefeller, January-May 1944 (Box 39, Folder 359)
  - Outgoing Correspondence - David Rockefeller, June-December 1944 (Box 39, Folder 360)
  - Outgoing Correspondence - David Rockefeller, 1945 (Box 39, Folder 361)
  - Outgoing Correspondence - David Rockefeller, 1946-1947 (Box 39, Folder 362)
  - Outgoing Correspondence - David Rockefeller - Transcripts, 1920-1931, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 363)
  - Outgoing Correspondence - David Rockefeller - Transcripts, 1932-1943 (Box 40, Folder 364)
  - Outgoing Correspondence - David Rockefeller - File Copies, 1932-1943 (Box 40, Folder 365)
  - Outgoing Correspondence - David and Peggy Rockefeller, 1940, 1943, 1947-1948 (Box 40, Folder 366)
    Open for scholarly research with prior archival review.
  - Outgoing Correspondence - Laurance S. Rockefeller, 1915, 1921, 1925, 1927, 1929-1933, 1944-1947 (Box 40, Folder 367)
  - Outgoing Correspondence - Laurance S. Rockefeller, 1915, 1921, 1925, 1927, 1929-1933, 1944-1947 (Box 40, Folder 367A)
  - Outgoing Correspondence - Laurance and Mary Rockefeller, 1935, 1945, 1947 (Box 40, Folder 368)
  - Outgoing Correspondence - Nelson and Mary Rockefeller, 1929-1936, 1946-1948 (Box 40, Folder 369)
  - Outgoing Correspondence - Nelson and Mary Rockefeller, 1929-1936, 1946-1948 (Box 40, Folder 369A)
  - Incoming Correspondence - David and Peggy Rockefeller, 1923, 1938-1941, 1947 (Box 40, Folder 370)
  - Incoming Correspondence - Laurance S. Rockefeller, 1918, 1920-1921, 1924, 1928-1929, 1931, 1934, 1938, 1945, 1947, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 371)
  - Incoming Correspondence - Laurance S. Rockefeller, 1918, 1920-1921, 1924, 1928-1929, 1931, 1934, 1938, 1945, 1947, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 371A)
  - Incoming Correspondence - Mary French Rockefeller, 1944, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 372)
  - Incoming Correspondence - Mary Todhunter Clark Rockefeller, 1929, 1947, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 373)
  - Incoming Correspondence - Mary Todhunter Clark Rockefeller, 1929, 1947, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 373A)
  - Incoming Correspondence - Rodman Rockefeller, 1937 (Box 40, Folder 374)
  - Children's Nurses Correspondence - Name Index (Box 41, Folder 375)
  - Children's Nurses Correspondence, 1915 (Box 41, Folder 376)
  - Children's Nurses Correspondence, 1916 (Box 41, Folder 377)
  - Children's Nurses Correspondence, 1917 (Box 41, Folder 378)
  - Children's Nurses Correspondence, 1920 (Box 41, Folder 379)
  - Children's Nurses Correspondence, 1921 (Box 41, Folder 380)
  - Children's Nurses Correspondence, January-February 1923 (Box 41, Folder 381)
  - Children's Nurses Correspondence, March 1923 (Box 41, Folder 382)
  - Children's Nurses Correspondence, April 1923 (Box 41, Folder 383)
  - Children's Nurses Correspondence, June-August 1923 (Box 41, Folder 384)
  - Children's Nurses Correspondence, 1924 (Box 41, Folder 385)
  - Children's Nurses Correspondence, 1925-1926 (Box 42, Folder 386)
  - Children's Nurses Correspondence, 1927-1930 (Box 42, Folder 387)
  - Children's Nurses Correspondence, 1931-1935 (Box 42, Folder 388)